Guide to the Michael Busch papers,1986-1996.
Busch, Michael papers, 1986-1996.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Michael Busch papers, 1986-1996.
7586
Michael, Busch 1954-
1 cubic ft; 1 folder
Subject files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files pertaining to Cornell and Ithaca lesbian and gay groups and issues, including AIDS Work of Tompkins County, Cornell AIDS Action, ACT UP Ithaca, and the Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Alliance.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Artist; AIDS Work of Tompkins County volunteer, and member of the Board of Directors; Ithaca Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Task Force Board of Directors member; editorial staff of Outlines; in 1988 he received the New York State Press Association Award for "Strong at the Broken Places," an article detailing his relationship with his friend Daniel, who was dying.
At Cornell, member of Cornell AIDS Action; member of the Working Group on Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual Issues which was formed by President Frank Rhodes in 1993; active in the process which led the University to offer domestic partner benefits to same-sex partners of faculty and staff; also active in creating the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Resource Office.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files pertaining to Cornell and Ithaca lesbian and gay groups and issues, including AIDS Work of Tompkins County, Cornell AIDS Action, ACT UP Ithaca, the Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Alliance, a Cornell gay and bisexual men's support group, and records from both the LGB Working group at Cornell and from the LGBRO (Lesbian Gay Bisexual Resource Office).
Also, handouts, Gay Games related advertising, broadsides, and other material collected in June 1994 in New York City; also material concerning the Stonewall 25 year celebration.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Busch, Michael,1954-; ACT UP Ithaca (Organization); AIDS Work of Tompkins County.; Alliance (Cornell University); Cornell University.Cornell AIDS Action.; Gay Games
Subjects:
Gays--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Lesbians--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Gay athletes.; Stonewall Riot, New York, N.Y., 1969.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Notes by Busch on the contents of the collection (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Have You Ever Wondered..." brochure design materials (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Support group correspondence & flyers (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Support groups handouts, articles (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Resource materials for gay and bisexual men's support groups (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Guided discussions (for support groups) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Tompkins County AIDS Task Force materials (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cornell AIDS Action Program, Jan. '95 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cornell AIDS Action, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Cornell AIDS Actoin Referral Network (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cornell AIDS Action brochure (Box 1, Folder 11)
- March on Washington, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- ACT-UP Ithaca materials, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- NGLTF member materials, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Includes flyer from Union Square park Rally as part of 1990 Gay Pride in NYC as well as text of Urvashi Vaid's speech that day.
- Gay in America series from the San Francisco Examiner, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Names Project Memorial Quilt at Cornell, 1993, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- World AIDS Day, Service of Remembrance materials, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- World AIDS Day, Service of Remembrance materials, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Alliance (Box 1, Folder 19)
- LGB Working Group, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- LGB Working Groups: Domestic Partner Benefits (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Domestic Partner Benefits/Net (?) (Box 1, Folder 22)
- LGBRO Advisory Group, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- LGBRO Review Panel, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Portrait: art show, 1995-04 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Stonewall 25 celebration in NYC ephemera, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Support groups addresses and birthday lists, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- 2 news sheets containing full page ads for the Lesbian Avengers (Folder 1)